maven.org 2017-12-20

# Privacy Policy – Sonatype

**Effective 21 September, 2016** , at Sonatype, Inc. ("Sonatype" or "our", or "us" or "we"), we respect the privacy rights of our online visitors and recognize the importance of protecting the information we collect about you. Our Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we collect and use the personal information you decide to share. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. This Privacy Policy applies to our website located at  **www.sonatype.com** ,  **www.maven.org**  and its related subdomains (collectively, the "Site") and all products and services we offer on the Site (together with the Site, the "Service").

**EU-U.S. Privacy Shield**

We participate in and have certified our compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. We are committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>.

We are responsible for the processing of personal data that we receive, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on our behalf. We comply with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, we are subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

We comply with the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from Switzerland. We have certified that we adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

By using or accessing the Service, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

Note that if you download software or otherwise purchase products or services through the Site or Service, use of such products or services is subject to the separate Sonatype license or other terms and conditions applicable to such product or service.

**The Information We Collect and How We Use It**

In general, you can use our Service without providing us with any personal information. However, there are instances where you must provide us with certain personal information in order to receive full access to the Service or to assist us in delivering a superior level of customer service. In such instances, we may collect the following types of information:

  * Registration Information - When you register with Sonatype, you provide us with certain personal information, such as first and last name, e-mail address, username, and an account password. We may use this information to contact you regarding notifications about the Service or new products and services we make available. We may also contact you, including by e-mail, with respect to any transaction you enter into with us, such as purchasing a product or service, making a support or sales inquiry, and the like.
  * Log Information - When you access the Service, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website and our analytics platform may capture additional information about use of our Site. This information may include information such as your Internet Protocol address, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personal information.
  * Cookies and other Tracking Technologies - Technologies such as: cookies or similar technologies are used by Sonatype and our marketing and technology partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the Service, tracking users' movements around the Site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. We may use cookies to improve our Service including by storing user preferences and tracking user trends. We also use cookies in our advertising services to help advertisers and publishers serve and manage ads across the web. We or our third party advertisers may set a cookie in your browser when you visit a website or click on an ad supported by our advertising services. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.
  * We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personal information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.
  * Local Storage Objects (Flash/HTML5)

We may use Local Storage such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use Local Storage such as HTML 5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

  * Order Information - If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personal information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number and expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, need to return an item, or otherwise have customer service or support issues, we will use this information to contact and assist you.
  * User Communications - When you send email or other communications to us, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve the Service.
  * We purchase lead data about our potential customers from third parties and combine it with information we already have about you, to create more tailored business leads.

By using the Service, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States.

**Children Under Age 13**

Sonatype does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on the Service. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at: [privacy@sonatype.com](mailto:privacy@sonatype.com).

**Sharing Your Information with Third Parties**

We will not share your personal information to third parties except in the following limited circumstances:

  * We have your consent.
  * We may share your personal information with our subsidiaries, affiliated companies or service partners for the purpose of processing your personal information on our behalf or to assist us with marketing, advertising or product/service offerings and fulfillment of orders. For example, we may provide personal information to our service providers for direct emailing of our newsletters, online surveys or notifications of our product/service offerings. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with appropriate confidentiality measures.
  * We may also share your personal information with a business partner or independent reseller (either within or outside the United States) so that the business partner or independent reseller can contact you and facilitate the support, renewal, and purchase of our products and services. You may receive a communication directly from one of our business partners or independent resellers. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance appropriate confidentiality measures. To find out the names and locations of the business partners and/or independent resellers to whom we have provided your information, please contact us at the address given at the end of this Privacy Policy.
  * We have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, and to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations thereof, detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of Sonatype, its users or the public as required or permitted by law.
  * We become involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of our assets. In this event, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

We may share with third parties aggregate, non-personal information. Such information does not identify you individually.

**Choice/Opt-out**

We provide you with the opportunity to "opt-out" of having your personal information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference at the time the information is collected.

If you no longer wish to receive our promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in the applicable message, by setting preferences as may be otherwise indicated on the Site or by contacting Sonatype at the address set forth at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

We will also send you service related email announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our Service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. You do not have an option to opt out of these emails, which are not promotional in nature.

We share your personal information with other companies so that they can market their products or services to you. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us at [privacy@sonatype.com](mailto:privacy@sonatype.com). If you receive a marketing communication from our subsidiaries, business partners or independent resellers, you should opt-out with that entity directly.

**Links**

This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Sonatype. The Site may contain links to other third party websites. Even if the third party is affiliated with Sonatype through a business partnership or otherwise, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Site to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personal information.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Surveys or Contests**

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personal information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). We use this information to notify contest winners and award prizes.

We use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests; that company is prohibited from using our users' personal information for any other purpose. We will not share the personal information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.

**Customer Testimonials**

We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personal information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@sonatype.com](mailto:privacy@sonatype.com).

**Sonatype Blog**

Our Web site offers a publicly accessible blog. Our blog is managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.

**Accessing and Updating Personal Information**

Upon your request, Sonatype will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information.  To request this information please contact us at [privacy@sonatype.com](mailto:privacy@sonatype.com).  

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove or deactivate it by emailing our Customer Support at [privacy@sonatype.com](mailto:privacy@sonatype.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed [on our about us page](https://www.sonatype.com/About-Sonatype). We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

**Retention**

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@sonatype.com](mailto:privacy@sonatype.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number or your password), we encrypt that information using reasonable security both during transmission and once we receive it. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at [privacy@sonatype.com](mailto:privacy@sonatype.com).

**Enforcement**

Sonatype regularly reviews its compliance with this Privacy Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or Sonatype's treatment of personal information by emailing us at: [privacy@sonatype.com](mailto:privacy@sonatype.com) or by writing to us at:

Privacy Matters   
Sonatype, Inc.  
8161 Maple Lawn Blvd, Suite 250  
Fulton, MD 20759

We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer or personal data that cannot be resolved between Sonatype and an individual.

**Terms of Service, Notices and Revisions**

Please also see our Terms of Service, which describe the restrictions, disclaimers, indemnification and limitation of liability governing the use of the Service. The Terms of Service also further describe our Service and the information we use.

**Notification of Privacy Policy Changes**

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us online, email us at [privacy@sonatype.com](mailto:privacy@sonatype.com), call us at 1.877.866.2836, or write to us at:

Sonatype, Inc.  
8161 Maple Lawn Blvd, Suite 250  
Fulton, MD 20759
